<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-08-11T20:08:49+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">PC Review</title><subtitle>Welcome to my new blog running on Jekyll</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Acer Predator Orion 9000</title><link href="/desktopcomputers/acer-predator-orion-9000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Acer Predator Orion 9000" /><published>2019-07-31T18:42:07+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-31T18:42:07+00:00</updated><id>/desktopcomputers/acer-predator-orion-9000</id><content type="html" xml:base="/desktopcomputers/acer-predator-orion-9000/">&lt;p&gt;Announced in the middle of last year, but only now becoming available to buy in the UK. Acer’s Predator Orion 9000 made headlines thanks to its eye-catching design coupled with ultra-high-end components including processors with up to eighteen cores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can buy the Predator Orion 9000 directly from Acer’s website (currently on a waiting list). There are two models available, starting from £2,999 for the 6-core version and rising to a whopping £4,999 for the ten-core version with dual graphics cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Acer Predator Orion 9000 is a huge, imposing beast of a PC both inside and out. Housed in Acer’s ‘monolithic’ custom-designed system case, the Orion 9000 features an angular space-age design with customisable RGB lighting, easily removable side panels and plenty of space inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s so big and heavy that Acer has decided to fit it with a pair of wheels at the rear so you can lug it around behind you like a luggage trolley. It’s also fitted with two sturdy handles at the top to make it easier and safer to lift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acer_Predator_Orion_9000_1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the front, there’s a handy pull-out bar purpose-built as a place to hang your gaming headphones. Acer has also thrown in a DVD RAM drive for good measure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you’d expect from a PC at this price point, the build quality is excellent, and because it’s designed entirely by Acer rather than built from off-the-shelf components, everything fits together perfectly, including the Predator Orion 9000’s custom-designed Icetunnel 2.0 cooling system which forms an integral part of the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Icetunnel 2.0 maintains four distinct thermal zones within the case, separating off the power supply from the GPU, CPU and storage areas, each of which is delivered its own carefully controlled share of cool air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Five RGB-illuminated 120mm fans are installed: one at the rear, two at the top and two more at the front of the case. The top two are fitted to the dual 120mm radiator forming part of a Predator-branded Cooler Master liquid processor cooler. There’s plenty of additional RGB lighting throughout the case which can easily be configured to your own preferred colours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acer_Predator_Orion_9000_1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also see: Best gaming PCs and Best gaming laptops
Processor and memory&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At launch, the Predator Orion 9000’s headline-grabbing specs included support for Core i7 and Core i9 Processors, including Intel’s Extreme Edition 18-core Core i9-7980XE chip. However, only two versions of the PC are being made available in the UK, neither of which supports this flagship CPU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, you can opt for the 6-core 3.5GHz Core i7-7800X in the entry-level system or the 10-core 3.30 GHz Core i9-7900X in the high-end version. Don’t worry, though, both of these processors are quite bonkers enough for a gaming PC, as you can see in our performance evaluation below.
Storage&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The less expensive model comes with a 2TB hard drive and a 256GB SSD preinstalled, which increases to 4TB and 512GB respectively if you opt for the pricier system. There’s plenty of room for additional storage in the case too, with room for up to six drives in total.
Motherboard&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Custom-designed for the Predator Orion 9000, the Acer PO9-900 motherboard isn’t one you can buy off-the-shelf, and no detailed list of specs is provided either. However, the key features are an Intel X299 Express chipset to handle the Skylake-X processors and eight RAM slots, supporting up to 128GB of DDR4 in total (of which 16GB or 32GB is installed at purchase time).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acer_Predator_Orion_9000_1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also includes three M.2 slots, Gigabit ethernet, Wireless-AC Wi-Fi and Bluetooth 4.2 Sound is provided by on-board Sound BlasterX Pro surround gaming audio engine. You also get four x16 PCI Express slots, which brings us on to…
Graphics&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the UK the entry-level model comes fitted with a GTX 1080 TI, although there’s plenty of room to double up to a multi-card configuration as found in the high-end version which comes with dual GTX 1080 TI cards as standard. At launch, the PC was shown with up to four Radeon Vega 64 cards installed but, like the 18-core version, this configuration doesn’t look likely to appear in the UK.
Performance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we dive into the test results, you should note that our review sample was built to a different specification than either of the models available in the UK. Our test configuration included the more expensive Core i9-7900X processor but with a single GTX 1080 Ti graphics card rather than the twin cards found in the pricier model on Acer’s website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would, therefore, expect gaming performance to be at a similar level to the lower-end £2,999 system combined with general computing benchmark scores closer to the £4,999 system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Predator Orion 9000 includes some super-high-end hardware which, as you might imagine, delivers excellent performance for gaming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it’s the extreme multi-tasking capability of the Core-i9 7900X which makes it so expensive, and this is of little real-world benefit when it comes to gaming. Even general- purpose benchmarks show minimal advantages outside of specialist applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you like to play games while rendering 4K video at the same time, then that might be a different matter, but for the vast majority of gamers, this PC is an expensive luxury.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Announced in the middle of last year, but only now becoming available to buy in the UK. Acer’s Predator Orion 9000 made headlines thanks to its eye-catching design coupled with ultra-high-end components including processors with up to eighteen cores.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">PC Specialist Vulcan S2</title><link href="/desktopcomputers/pc-specialist-vulcan-s2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PC Specialist Vulcan S2" /><published>2019-04-14T17:44:05+00:00</published><updated>2019-04-14T17:44:05+00:00</updated><id>/desktopcomputers/pc-specialist-vulcan-s2</id><content type="html" xml:base="/desktopcomputers/pc-specialist-vulcan-s2/">&lt;p&gt;This £1,394 machine is built around two key components: an Intel Core i7-9700 processor and an Nvidia GeForce RTX 2070 graphics card. You’ll need to buy it direct from PC Specialist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s a lot of power for this price, and it squares up well against its key rival. The Overclockers Hoplite originally arrived at £1,479, but now it costs £1,299 – so it’s £100 cheaper than the PC Specialist machine. That rig relies on an AMD Ryzen 7 2700X CPU and RTX 2060 graphics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Vulcan S2 is protected by the standard PC Specialist deal, which is a three-year labour deal with one year of parts protection and one month of collection coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out our best gaming PC chart.
Design &amp;amp; Build&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PC Specialist has used one of its own enclosures for this machine. It’s called the PCS P209, and it nails most of the current trends. There’s a tempered glass side panel, a magnetic dust filter on top, and a slab of metal at the front.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It looks like loads of other recent cases – including the Kolink Phalanx RGB used by the Overclockers Hoplite. That PC’s enclosure also has a tempered glass side panel and a dust filter in the roof, but its front-mounted trio of RGB LED fans are more eye-catching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PC Specialist Vulcan S2 case&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The P209 is 455mm tall and 390mm deep, so it’s smaller than the Kolink – that unit is 510mm talk and 445mm deep. That bodes well for fitting the Vulcan into smaller spaces. Build quality is impressive, too – the steel used throughout is sturdy, so we have no concerns there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are slim air intake vents at the front, and at the rear there’s a 120mm exhaust. Air intake is handled by two 120mm fans that are attached to the Cooler Master MasterLiquid Lite 240 processor cooler. That’s a slight concern – because it means that cool air coming in will immediately be heated. This shouldn’t be a huge problem due to the Vulcan’s mid-range components, but the Overclockers is better-equipped due to its trio of intake fans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The top of the P209 only has two USB 2.0 ports and one USB 3.0 connection – there’s no faster USB 3.1 port. It’s the same as the Kolink case, but it’s not particularly good for fast data transfers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the inside the P209 remains conventional. A PSU shroud hides the Corsair power supply, and PC Specialist has done a good job of keeping cables neat – so airflow isn’t disrupted and internal access is easy. Lighting is handled by a patterned strip of RGB LEDs down the front panel and a strip of lights to illuminate the hardware inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, in some areas the P209 is basic. Behind the motherboard there’s only room to add single 2.5- and 3.5in hard disks, and the hard disk option is poor – there’s no dedicated bay and no tool-free installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PC Specialist Vulcan S2 ports&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Hoplite’s Kolink case is better here, with pairs of 2.5- and 3.5in hard disk bays. That case also has 370mm of graphics card clearance – 50mm more than the PCS P209.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Vulcan’s case is smart, sturdy, small and accessible, and it has RGB LEDs. But it doesn’t have the best port selection, and the slightly cheaper Overclockers has more room to grow – as well as more extravagant design.
Specs &amp;amp; Performance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Nvidia GeForce RTX 2070 sits in the middle of Nvidia’s latest range. It uses the Turing architecture, which means you get the latest architectural improvements – as well as ray-tracing and DLSS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Vulcan’s RTX 2070 is made by Palit, and it uses the GPU’s stock configuration with no overclocking. That means you get 2,304 stream processors, 8GB of memory and a boost clock of 1,620MHz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lack of overclocking doesn’t stop the RTX 2070 outstripping the cheaper Overclockers’ RTX 2060. The Gigabyte-made card in that machine has a small overclock, with the 1,680MHz standard turbo speed improved to 1,770MHz, but that GPU only has 1,920 stream processors and 6GB of memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PC Specialist Vulcan S2 Nvidia RTX 2070&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unsurprisingly, the RTX 2070 was better in our benchmarks. Its Sky Diver result of 44,637 is more than 1,000 points ahead of the Hoplite. The PC Specialist handled Total War: Warhammer 2 at 1080p and Ultra settings at 152fps – five frames ahead of the Hoplite. At Ultra the Vulcan ran at 91fps – a four-frame advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the tougher Ghost Recon: Wildlands, at 1080p and at Ultra settings, the Vulcan still blasted through with an average of 65fps – easily playable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Vulcan played games at 1440p, too: in Warhammer and Ghost Recon at maximum settings it averaged 62- and 51fps respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RTX 2070 can’t handle 4K, though. It only managed good framerates at Medium settings – at Ultra, in both games, minimum framerates dipped below 30fps. You’re either going to get stuttering gameplay or you’ll have to drop the quality levels, and neither is ideal.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This £1,394 machine is built around two key components: an Intel Core i7-9700 processor and an Nvidia GeForce RTX 2070 graphics card. You’ll need to buy it direct from PC Specialist.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Huawei MateBook 13</title><link href="/laptops/huawei-matebook-13/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Huawei MateBook 13" /><published>2019-04-10T11:32:05+00:00</published><updated>2019-04-10T11:32:05+00:00</updated><id>/laptops/huawei-matebook-13</id><content type="html" xml:base="/laptops/huawei-matebook-13/">&lt;p&gt;Huawei’s MateBook X and MateBook X Pro are some of the best looking laptops on the market, but they each came with a few compromises - and hefty price tags. That’s all the more reason to to be excited about the MateBook 13, which brings the same style at a friendlier price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Announced at CES 2019, the MateBook 13 looks an awful lot like the X and X Pro - with a few compromises, to be fair - but shaves a few hundred off the price, turning it into a competitive rival to the likes of the MacBook Air or the new Dell XPS 13 and potentially one of the best laptops of 2019.
Price and availability&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MateBook 13 is out now, and comes in two models - with specs varying slightly between regions. In the UK, the base model is £899 (available from Amazon or Currys) and comes with a Core i5 processor and 256GB of storage. The higher end model - the one we were given to review - costs £1099 (from Amazon, Currys, Very, Argos, or AO) and includes a faster i7 processor and double the storage, 512GB. Both models have the same 8GB RAM and integrated Intel graphics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specs in the US are almost the same. The base model is the same - a Core i5 processor and 256GB storage, though it comes in a silver finish - and will cost you $999 (from Amazon, B&amp;amp;H, or Newegg), but the pricier version is a little different. In addition to the i7 processor and 512GB storage, the US model includes an Nvidia MX150 graphics card for $1299 (from Amazon, B&amp;amp;H, or Newegg).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering that the MacBook Air starts from £1,199/$1,199 for a model with less storage than Huawei’s, while the XPS 13 starts from £999/$899 for an i3 processor, that pricing is already seriously competitive, and anyone looking for a compact, portable laptop around that price point should at least be considering the MateBook 13.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple-ish aesthetics&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve seen any of Huawei’s recent laptops then the MateBook 13 will appear immediately familiar. There’s the same grey finish (with silver on the cheaper American model), with minimal bezels, an expansive touchpad, and all-metal construction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will probably also appear familiar if you’ve seen Apple’s latest MacBook and MacBook Air, and it’d be hard not to admit that Huawei’s designers owe a debt to Apple’s. That’s partly what will fuel the inevitable comparisons to the new Air, and the MateBook comes out surprisingly well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 13in, 2160 x 1440 touchscreen display is in the same 3:2 aspect ratio Huawei’s favoured for a few years. It’s a squarer, boxier format than you might be used to, which results in a lot of letter-boxing when you watch movies or TV, but leaves you with plenty of vertical screen real estate when you’re working or browsing the web. That makes it ideal as a work device, if less optimal for curling up in bed with Netflix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The keyboard is pretty lovely, with comfortable key spacing and a really responsive, short action. These are very low-profile keys, which might take a little getting used to for some, but undeniably easy to type on. The trackpad is a bit less appealing - the size is great, but there’s a very slight stickiness to it, with just a bit too much drag for my liking. It feels slightly wrong to me, in a way that’s hard to pin down, and I’d recommend trying to check the laptop out in person if you can to make sure it won’t bother you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Huawei’s MateBook X and MateBook X Pro are some of the best looking laptops on the market, but they each came with a few compromises - and hefty price tags. That’s all the more reason to to be excited about the MateBook 13, which brings the same style at a friendlier price.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Razer Blade Pro 17</title><link href="/laptops/razer-blade-pro/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Razer Blade Pro 17" /><published>2019-03-03T15:56:05+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-03T15:56:05+00:00</updated><id>/laptops/razer-blade-pro</id><content type="html" xml:base="/laptops/razer-blade-pro/">&lt;p&gt;Not long ago gaming laptops were big, bulky beasts that were more akin to a portable PC tower than a sexy, sleek laptop. However, companies like Razer have made leaps and bounds in the laptop design department over the past few years and now offer products that are both powerful and sleek.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Razer’s Blade Pro 17 is the company’s top-of-the-line 17.3in laptop for gamers, offering desktop-level graphics in a chassis that’s not only 25 percent thinner than its predecessor, but small enough to fit in most 15in laptop bags too. Is it enough to solidify its place amongst the best gaming laptops available? We think so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve spent some time gaming on the Razer Blade Pro 17, and here’s our full review.
Blade Pro 17 - Price &amp;amp; Availability&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you thought the £1,699/$1,899 starting price of the standard Razer Blade 15 was high, you might wince at the £2,399/$2,499 starting price for the Razer Blade Pro. It doesn’t end there either, as you can pick up the mid-range model for £2,679/$2,799 and the high-end model for £3,079/$3,199.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those interested in buying the Razer Blade Pro 17 can do so from Razer along with the likes of Amazon, Scan and Currys PC World.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The high-end price tag puts it in direct competition not only with Razer’s own high-end Blade 15 (2019), but the likes of the Alienware Area 51M (from £1,948) and budget-friendly Aorus 15 X9 (from £1,999).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a breakdown of the Razer Blade Pro 17 pricing to give you a better idea of what’s on offer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;144Hz FHD display, 16GB RAM, 512GB, RTX 2060 – £2,399 / $2,499 / €2,669
144Hz FHD display, 16GB RAM, 512GB, RTX 2070 Max-Q – £2,679 / $2,799 / €3,049
144Hz FHD display, 16GB RAM, 512GB, RTX 2080 Max-Q – £3,079 / $3,199 / €3,499
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blade Pro 17 - Design &amp;amp; Build&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Razer Blade Pro 17 follows a similar design aesthetic to the rest of the Razer collection, including the Razer Blade 15 and even the Razer Phone 2, complete with a black-and-green colour scheme and a bold, angular design that looks sleek. It’s certainly a step away from the in-your-face gaming laptop design on offer by the likes of Alienware, with the understated Razer Blade Pro 17 looking just as good at the office as it does playing games at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chassis of the Razer Blade Pro 17 features an anodized matte black finish which in addition to looking good and keeping fingerprints at bay, helps the laptop stay scratch- and scuff-free, although we’re not in the position to start defacing it in the name of testing. It should also prove quite sturdy, as the entire chassis is milled from a single block of aluminium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite featuring a 17.3in display, the 0.6mm bezels that surround it allow the chassis to stay relatively small – in fact, the Razer Blade Pro 17 is 25% smaller than the last-gen Pro and boasts similar dimensions to 15in laptops we’ve used in the past, measuring in at 395 x 360 x 19.9mm and weighing 2.75kg. We can confirm that it’ll just about fit into a 15in laptop bag too, making it easier to transport between home and work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the chassis magic, the Razer Blade Pro 17 has a larger surface for cooling when compared to the 2018 variant, which translates to better heat dissipation and better performance during long, intense gaming sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blade Pro 17 - Specs &amp;amp; Performance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much like with the display, regardless of the model you choose, you’re going to get a 9th-gen six-core i7-9750H processor with a 2.6GHz base speed, boosted to 4.5GHz with Max Turbo. It’s the same story with RAM and storage, with all variants boasting 16GB Dual-Channel DDR4 2667MHz RAM and a 512GB PCIe NVMe SSD alongside an additional M.2 slot to further upgrade the storage post-purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only real difference is in terms of graphics; all feature Nvidia RTX cards, but only the mid and top tier laptops feature Max-Q cards. The base model comes with the RTX 2060, while the mid-tier option boasts the RTX 2070 Max-Q and the top-tier sports the RTX 2080 Max-Q. If that’s not enough, you could always pick up Razer’s Core X eGPU to house a desktop card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For reference, we’ve been testing the base model with a 9th-gen core i7, 16GB of DDR4 RAM and an Nvidia RTX 2060 GPU, and performance is what we’d expect from an entry-level RTX, although there are cheaper, more powerful options on the market if you can do without the Blade Pro 17’s sleek design.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Not long ago gaming laptops were big, bulky beasts that were more akin to a portable PC tower than a sexy, sleek laptop. However, companies like Razer have made leaps and bounds in the laptop design department over the past few years and now offer products that are both powerful and sleek.</summary></entry></feed>